字幕校对+特效: 月亮花@MySiLU思路高清
海军航空兵
为了对抗恐怖攻击威胁
军方已拟出全新计划
运用最先进的
实验性科技
目的是消灭
世界各地的敌人
4百多名飞行员申请参与此计划
3名顶尖飞官雀屏中选
片名：绝密飞行
鹰爪1号请求指挥中心下达指令
Talon 1 requesting Bitching Betty relay Combat Control commands.
收到，鹰爪1号
Roger, Talon 1.
指挥中心正在传送
Central Prime is transmitting...
加密地形自动侦测卫星影像
...encrypted satellite auto-terrain comparison.
这是指挥官
Talons, this is Operator.
攻击指挥员发出最后指令
PAYCOM has given his final tasking orders.
前往攻击目标，准确执行任务
You are to proceed to target and prosecute with precision.
你们是美国海军飞行员
Now, remember, you are pilots of the u.s. Navy.
一定要有完美表现
I expect nothing less than perfection.
收到，执行攻击任务
Roger, skipper. Activating tactical music.
鹰爪2号，请确认
Countermeasure is silent party. Talon 2, confirm.
确认，执行任务
Talon 2 confirms. Music on.
这次任务没有风险
Risk assessment is we have a clean mission status.
展开攻击
Attack commencing.
你死了
Gotcha.
导弹来袭…导弹来袭…
Missile lock. Missile lock.
西边有地对空导弹发射基地 我们遭到导弹攻击
Talon 3, there's a sAM site on the west wall. We got birds in the air.
地对空导弹发射基地被消灭
Talon 2, the sAM site's been erased.
我可不是好惹的
Now, that's how you do it.
鹰爪3号，好样的
Talon 3, that was shit-hot!
鹰爪1号，该你上场了
Talon 1, I expect the same out of you.
准备发射蓝灌导弹轰爆目标
Arming Blue Ferret for penetration detonation.
导弹启动
Missile armed. Missile armed.
海军空战演练场 斐伦，内华达州
一百分满分，没错
Yep, 100 over 100. That's correct.
分数可靠吗？
And I can rely on these numbers?
这又不是花式溜冰 他们的命中率是百分百
Well, this isn't figure skating, Ray. You either score or you don't.
国家指挥当局非常满意
National Command Authority's duly impressed.
并同意进行第二阶段
They've given us the go-ahead on phase two.
知道吗？
You know what?
你应该来华府一趟 亲自向参议员做报告
You should come to D.C. and make the presentation to the senators.
芮准将就是这么做
That's how Admiral Rickover got things done.
你也想升准将，对吧？
Admiral. You get my meaning?
我还是让你去进行游说吧
No, I'm flattered, but you do the lobbying.
我不搞政治这一套
Politics is for politicians.
上校？ 我再跟你联络
Captain? I'll get back to you.
冰柜有冰棒，自己拿
There's Popsicles in the cooler.
有葡萄口味吗？ 有葡萄口味吗？
Got any grape? Any grape?
只剩一根，不要抢
I believe there is one left, and don't lose your dignity.
谢了
Oh, thank you.
大伙儿坐吧 接得好
All right, take a seat. Nice catch.
有什么地方需要改进？
Talk to me. Where are the holes? How can we improve?
快说，我没有耐心
Come on. I'm not a patient man.
我急着甩掉地对空导弹 来不及摧毁目标
sorry, I got caught up on that west wall. I had to pull out...
战争是团队运动
War is a team sport.
当攻击目标太多 队友就得互相支援
Those AAA sites were thick. Gave extra time to the sAM sites.
没错，没有需要改进的地方
see, that's your answer. There really was no room for improvement.
韦上尉做的很对
Actually, what Lieutenant Wade did was right.
她摧毁敌方的通讯系统 找出地对空导弹发射基地
she took out their communications and exposed their sAM sites...
好让亨利一举消灭它 这就是我的绝招
...so Henry could lay it down. That's what I do.
一切都很完美 我完全同意
I mean, it was perfect. "Perfect." I'll go along with that.
我只是不想看到你这么臭屁
Much as I hate to see that smile of yours get any smugger.
你脸红啦？
You blushing?
我有好消息
I've got good news.
我们要被派到航空母舰
Tell us we got a carrier, skipper, come on.
没错
Affirmative.
亚伯拉罕林肯号
The USS Abraham Lincoln.
马狄克舰长是我的老同学
Captain's an old classmate of mine, Dick Marshfield.
你应该也认识他 我说的舰长就是他
I believe you two know each other. He was the captain I told you about.
他当年是个顶尖飞行员 他也是个黑人
Hell of a pilot in his day. He's black too. He's black.
这个飞行中队有新队员
I'm also gonna be expanding your squadron.
会有一架新战机加入你们
On the carrier, you'll be joined by a new wingman.
第四架战机？
A fourth wingman?
我以为只有三架鹰爪战机
Wait, I thought there were only three Talons in existence.
亨利，怎么了？你好像很不爽
What is the problem, Purcell? You look like you been hit in the gut.
咱们在一起很久，合作无间
For one, captain, we've been flying together for a long time and it's good.
而且这数字不吉祥
And four is an unlucky number.
不吉祥？ 不是质数
unlucky? It's not a prime number.
质数只能被和本身整除
Prime numbers can only be divided by one or itself.
3就是质数，三位一体
Three is prime. The Holy Trinity.
正反合的辩证法则
Thesis and antithesis come together and form the synthesis...
这是美国海军，不是哲学课
This is not a seminar on metaphysics. This is the u.s. Navy.
星期三清晨五点整出发 解散
Now, we ship out Wednesday at 0500. Dismissed.
我还要说
Okay. If he'd let me finish, I was gonna say...
三人行、三人成虎 三剑客
...Three's Company, Three Stooges, Three Musketeers, three-peat...
三好球出局 三民主义
..."three strikes, you're out," "Three Times a Lady."
三次元 大三元
Three dimensions. Three blind mice.
别忘了还有3P
There's menage a trois. Don't forget that one.
敬咱们三个最佳搭档
To the original three.
干杯 干杯
Cheers to that. Cheers.
干杯 敬各位朋友
Cheers. And assorted guests.
干杯
Cheers.
我马上就回来
I'll be back in a second.
我得去尿尿
I gotta go pee-pee.
拜托
That's nasty.
至少她自己会大小便
At least she's potty-trained. I'll give her that.
奇普欧 不可能
Chip O'Dell. No way.
一定是他 第四个队友一定是他
Yeah, it's gotta be him. Hey, Henry, our fourth wing. It's gotta be him.
他一直想抢你们的位置
He tried to manipulate his way into the program, but you two beat him.
不过麦贝琪比他更高杆
Yeah, but Becky Martinez could fly circles around O'Dell.
两个女飞官？不可能啦 那可不一定
Two out of the four are women? No. Hey, you never know.
他好大男人主义哦 且慢，这不是真的
God, you're such a chauvinist. Hold on, now, that's not true.
我很乐意向女性低头认输
I bow down before the superiority of the opposite sex in many respects.
不过有时候
But from time to time...
她们也该向我低头
...I believe they should bow down before me.
拜托 卡莉，你不同
Oh, please. Kara. Kara, listen. You're different.
你独一无二 没错
You are a singularity. Absolutely.
你是大自然的突变
You're a freak. Of nature.
多谢夸奖哦 不客气
Well, thank you, Henry, I think. You are very welcome.
你知道我怎么想吗？
You know what I think?
别想，喝就对了
Don't think. Drink.
玩得开心点
Have fun.
亚伯拉罕林肯号，菲律宾海
很壮观的夜空
spectacular night, huh?
既黑暗又神秘 班，你不喜欢惊喜吗？
Dark and mysterious, sir. Don't you like surprises, Ben?
他来了
Well, here he comes now.
来见见你的新队友
Meet your new wingman.
让我介绍数字化战争的未来 提姆
Allow me to introduce the future of digital warfare. Tim?
请为提姆打开驾驶舱
Open for Tim, please.
燃料：催化甲烷
Fuel, catalyzed A1 methane.
机身：陶瓷合成金属
Exoskeleton, metal-ceramic composite.
气动弹性机翼
Aeroelastic wings.
脉冲爆震引擎外加 双混合冲压式涡轮引擎
Pulse detonation engine with twin hybrid scramjet turbos.
艾迪能在五英里外辨识身份
EDI's sensors can pick out a face five miles away.
那就订做三台吧 我要敞蓬，车牌上写我的名字
so we'll take three. Drop the top on mine, personalized license plate.
这是智慧型无人战机
so this is one of these smart uCAVs.
这么说未免太小看他了
Well, technically you could call it an unmanned Combat Aerial Vehicle.
你不会说航空母舰是艘帆船吧？
But that would be like calling this carrier a rowboat.
你说的对，这玩意我也懂
I feel you, captain. I know a bit about this.
这是量子处理器，对吧？ 对，这是第一台
This is quantum processing, right? Yeah, it's the first tested application.
每秒处理十兆位
Ten terabits a second.
无人战机为什么有驾驶舱？
so if it's a uCAV, why does it have a seat?
那是为了测试和维修
The cockpit's just for testing and maintenance.
艾迪他会自己飞
Otherwise, EDI flies all by himself.
你是说“它”吧？
You mean "itself," don't you, sir?
原来你说的就是这玩意儿
so this is what the fuss is all about.
这是超先进隐形战机
You're looking at VLO stealth, captain.
它的能力超越极限
It's got a brain like a quantum sponge.
它的表现会打破所有记录
And one day, its survivability is going to fly right off the charts.
韦上尉 幸会，长官
Lieutenant Wade. It's good to meet you, sir.
它果然令人汗为观止
It is a bag of chips, all right.
卜上尉 我的荣幸，长官
Lieutenant Purcell. Honored to meet you, sir.
它会取代我们大家
It will replace us all.
乔治，这看起来像科幻小说
Looks and sounds like science fiction, George.
科幻小说的情节也可能成真
Well, so did everything, once upon a time.
你说的对
Ain't that the truth.
贾先生，欢迎回来
Mr. Gannon. Good to have you back.
你之前的飞行中队仍然保持…
Your first squadron tour still holds some of the ship's most...
惊人的记录
...impressive records.
谢谢你，马舰长 记录一定会被打破
Thank you, Captain Marshfield. Records are made to be broken.
规矩也一样，这是你的作风
Rules too, if I remember your philosophy.
康上校，副舰长卡尔森
Captain Cummings, this is my X O, Mr. Carlson.
卡尔森
Carlson.
咱们待会在飞行甲板上见
Why don't you meet me up on the flight deck after you're through.
没问题 恭喜了，乔治
You bet. Congratulations, George.
谢谢 很高兴再见面，狄克
Thank you. Good to see you again, Dick.
我也是
You too.
它在发出低鸣声 不，艾迪是在动脑筋
It's humming. No, EDI's thinking.
动什么脑筋？ 查你们的底细
Thinking? Thinking about what, sir? You. All of you.
他在查你们的档案 你们所有的飞行记录
He's going over your files. He's reviewing all your flight logs.
让它飞一飞，看看它的能耐
Let's take it for a spin, see what it can do.
等到明天再说
No, no, no. Tomorrow.
你们得先做功课 功课？
First, you gotta do your homework. Homework?
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
EDI无人战机 极限深度侵略者
"EDI uCAV. Extreme Deep Invader."
也有人这么形容过我
Yeah, I've been called that a few times.
这笑话超冷的 是喔
I've heard that one. Yeah, right.
你好，帅哥
Well, hello, gorgeous.
EDI 深度攻击结构
武器系统与攻击战略
拜托，别偷拍，拜托
Please, no pictures, please. No pictures, please. Please.
好啦，尽管拍吧
Okay, take them. Take them. Take them.
门没锁
It's open.
休息时间
study break.
你很不用功哦
You are one big study break.
我天生聪明
Just a natural.
原来你是靠头脑把妹
so that is the appeal.
怪不得你专门
Okay, because I was really wondering how you manage...
泡金发尤物
...to pull a rocket scientist at every port.
你最好小心点 金发尤物可不好惹
You better be careful, Ben, you know. Hair bleach causes cancer in rats.
放心，我的经验丰富
Well, I'm not a rat. That's my appeal.
你很用功嘛 对啊
You checking out the drone? Yeah.
这玩意真的很精密复杂
Just barely skimmed the surface.
未来会是艾迪的时代 艾迪
We really are in the era of EDI. EDI.
我有没有提过我的养母？
Did I ever tell you about that foster mother I had?
体重一百五十公斤 没有
The one who weighed 350 pounds? No.
有一天她带了一只吉娃娃回家
Anyway, one day she comes home with this Chihuahua, right?
你猜他叫什么？艾迪
Guess what she named him. Eddie.
我又知道你另一个泡妞绝招 什么？
You know what I realized about you? What?
你老爱说养母的冷笑话
You got a foster mom for every situation.
我的童年悲惨，不用白不用
Hey, I lived through my childhood. I may as well use it, right?
是啊
That's right.
你同意马舰长的话
so tell me, you think Marshfield's right?
我们会被机器取代吗？
You think they're gonna trade us all in for that machine?
不可能，打仗要靠武器
No way. War is about tools. Think about it.
从徒手到棍棒，铜器到铁器
Claws to clubs, bronze to steel.
最顶尖的战士才能赢 或是女战士
Best guy with the best weapon wins. Or girl.
大家都知道你是捍卫女战士
And we all know who that is, don't we?
你这话好像有点酸溜溜哦
The dull thud of a Ben Gannon compliment.
嗯…
Well...
小心我的C罩杯
Oh, pardon my C cup.
休息时间结束
study break is over.
早安，林肯号
Good morning to the crew of the uss Abraham Lincoln.
任何异物都会破坏喷射引擎
Remember, foreign-object debris can ruin a jet engine.
大家一起检查飞行甲板
Let's keep our safety record. Scour that deck.
咱们都老了，怎么回事？
Hey. Feel like we got older, Dick. What the hell happened?
至少你的头发还在
Don't complain. You still got your hair.
也只剩一点了
Yeah. some of it.
老实说
Look, truth be told...
我并不想让你在我的舰上做实验
...I never wanted this little experiment of yours on my ship.
你不是唯一的一个人
Well, you're not hurting my feelings, Dick.
史准将也不赞成
Admiral spelling shared your point paper with me...
我会把你的意见反应上去
...and your objections were duly noted.
你一向都很有政治手腕 没办法，这是官僚制度
You always could work the politics. It's indispensable in a bureaucracy.
我的舰上可没有官僚制度
This isn't a bureaucracy, not out here.
当你急着使用全新武器系统
You rush a weapons system into service...
忽略必要的测试程序 就可能会死人
...you shortcut an operational test cycle, people might get killed.
没经过允许我绝对不敢乱来
You know I can't pick my nose here without 7000 people approving it.
没有人忽略任何程序
Nobody rushed a damn thing.
这项计划只是提早完成
Program is just ahead of schedule.
你忽略了这玩意
You missed this.
我在你们前面
I'm out first, boys.
我就跟在你屁股后面
I'm right on that ass.
你们先请吧
After you, ladies.
鹰爪2号升空
Talon 2, airborne.
鹰爪3号升空
Talon 3, airborne.
鹰爪号升空，航向2-5-4
Talon 1 is off and heading 2-5-4.
启动无人战机
Deploying unmanned Combat Aerial Vehicle...
极限深度侵略者
...Extreme Deep Invader now.
我没想到会有这一天
I never thought we would see this day.
我也没想到
Me neither, sir.
艾迪，你可以升空了
uCAV EDI, you have launch.
进行编队飞行，请确认
One to uCAV. Confirm flight link. Over.
编队飞行，确认
Flight link confirmed, Talon 1.
很高兴能加入飞行中队
It is good to be part of the squadron.
哇塞，他会讲话耶
What? Well, well, well. He can talk.
那有什么了不起 我朋友的宝马轿车也会说话
Big deal. I know a guy's BMW, does exactly the same thing.
给我影像
Picture, please.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
启动适应性逻辑系统
swarm logic activated.
班，艾迪是来向你学习
All right, Ben. EDI's here to learn from you.
你要把一身本领都教给他
so let's make sure these lessons are up to speed, all right?
那就开始上课吧
Well, then, let the schooling begin.
康上校
Captain Cummings.
请进来一下
Inside, please.
什么事？ 你有一项新任务
What's the deal? You, sir, have a new tasking order.
你们看到无人战机吗？
One to wing, anybody got a visual on the uCAV?
没看到 我也没看到
Negative, 1. Negative, 1.
快让它归队
We better find him and regroup.
别让它趴趴走
Before it takes a crap in its quantum pants.
等一下
Wait up. Hold on.
他在干什么？
What the hell is he doing?
他来了，他来了
Here he comes. Here he comes.
那个小兄弟在耍我们
I think little brother is messing with us.
你的位置永远在我右侧
uCAV, your position is always on my starboard side.
另一边
Other starboard.
超炫的
That's hot.
它没有心，不过蛮会飞的 这个锡人还不赖嘛
Got no heart, but it sure can fly. That's not bad for a tin man.
艾迪，你有新的呼号 你的呼号是锡人一世
EDI, it's official. You got a call sign. uCAV "Tin Man" EDI, the first.
呼叫飞行中队 请说
Operator to squadron. Go for Talons.
改变计划
There's been a change of plans.
你们有新的任务
We're giving you an emergency mission redirect. Repeat.
全新的紧急任务，收到吗？
That's an emergency redirect. Do you read me?
收到，什么任务？
Roger. Where's the fire, skipper?
攻击指挥员发出全新指令
PAYCOM has given us a brand-new tasking order.
请接收加密档案
Please access your encrypted file...
档名是备战状态指示
...named "Advanced War Vector scenarios."
档案打开了，请说
File's open. Go ahead.
防火墙密码是恐怖高峰会
All right. Firewall code is "Terror summit."
从备战状态升级为攻击行动
We are upgrading this file from a scenario to a tactical action plan.
重覆，这是攻击行动
Repeat, we are upgrading the file.
仰光
中情局得知三名恐怖组织首脑
CIA human intel has just learned that the heads of three terrorist cells...
将在24分钟后开会
...are about to meet in 24 minutes.
地点是缅甸的仰光市
The country is Myanmar. The city is Rangoon.
他们要商讨攻击美国本土
They're planning an imminent attack on U.S. soil.
无人战机怎么办？
One to Control, what about the uCAV?
艾迪要跟去观察你们的行动
EDI will observe your attack.
立刻前往目的地
Proceed to primary.
收到
Roger.
你只能进行观察，请确认
One to UCA V, confirm observation status only.
锡人确认
Tin Man confirms, Talon 1.
新座标上传完毕
New coordinates haVe been uploaded.
锡人，这是震撼教育
Baptism by fire, Tin Man.
1马赫
Mach 1.
2马赫
Mach 2.
3马赫
Mach 3.
4马赫
Mach 4.
电脑正在分析攻击目标
Primo's now analyzing the location. Here we go.
目标是这栋大楼
The primary is this building.
正在兴建中的国防部大厦
A new defense ministry still under construction.
14英尺厚混凝水泥屋顶
specs indicate 14-foot-thick cement roof...
以及强化钢梁
...with steel reinforcements.
我们的武器无法摧毁目标
Roger. We're not weaponized for something that thick.
重覆，无法摧毁目标
Repeat, not weaponized.
杀伤范围有多少人口？
This is 2. What's the population of the collateral area?
大楼本身空无一人 但是它位于仰光市中心
The building's unoccupied, but it's in the middle of downtown Rangoon.
这栋大楼的屋顶
This is 3. Talk to me about that roof.
用什么武器才能炸穿？
What's Primo advocate to ordinance and influence?
鹰爪战机没有适用的武器
Primo says Talons can't penetrate it.
这是唯一的机会 以后就逮不到他们了
This is our chance. We may never catch these bastards together again.
采用横向攻击
Try a lateral vector.
照他的话做
Just do what he says.
这是鹰爪号
This is 2 to Control. Risk assessment officer adVises...
横向攻击会造成数千人伤亡
...casualties from lateral vector will be in the thousands.
锡人拦截了间谍卫星讯号
Tin Man has integrated all network-centric spy satellites.
这是全新的资讯
Here is new data.
艾迪绕过中央电脑系统 正在发送机密影像
uCAV is bypassing Central Prime. He's distributing secure video stream.
语音分析
夏格艾胡力
身份确认
视网膜扫瞄
孙杰丁
身份确认
曼瑟珊苏丹
今年圣诞节我要这玩意当礼物
Look at that. Oh, yeah. Oh, now I know what I want for Christmas.
我们即将到达攻击目标
One to Control, we've entered our mission window.
63秒后到达目标
Six-three seconds to primary and counting.
快点，我们锁定目标了
Come on, Control, we have our targets.
快想出其它办法 这些恐怖份子是我们的囊中物
Come on. I need an alternative. We got these guys in the bull's-eye.
有另一个可行的方法
There is an alternatiVe, Combat Control.
无人战机，快说
Operator to uCAV. Talk to me. Give me something.
鹰爪战机挂载内爆式导弹
Squadron carries truncheon implosion bombs.
不行，威力不够强
Negative, will not work.
电脑说它无法达到穿透速度
Central Prime says truncheons can't achieve velocity for penetration.
只剩37秒，赶快解释
One to uCAV, 37 seconds to primary. Come on, explain.
极速垂直俯冲能增加导弹速度
DiVing dead Vertical at 2070 knots will increase truncheon Velocity.
导弹能够成功穿透屋顶
Bomb will successfully penetrate roof.
极速垂直俯冲晕厥机率是多少？
What's the blackout risk at vertical 2070?
七成三 23秒后到达目标
Seventy-three percent. Time on target is 23 seconds.
取消任务，不值得冒险 鹰爪号撤退
Call it off. It's not worth the risk. Operator to Talons, pull back.
让艾迪发射导弹 上校
EDI will plant the truncheon. Captain.
这就是无人战机的作用
This is what we built this machine for.
它不是血肉之躯 不会昏过去
There's no blood in those quantum veins. It can't black out.
重覆，让艾迪发射导弹
Operator to Talons, repeat, EDI will plant the truncheon.
不行，这项任务重大 让我执行任务
Control, negative, Control. Mission critical. One will prosecute.
这是3号，我挺你
This is 3 to 1. I got your back...
不过你若昏倒会造成重大伤亡
...but if you black out, you're gonna kill everyone.
放心，我不是那七成三的逊脚
Negative, 3. I did not get this far by being in the 73rd percentile.
我一定会成功
I like my odds.
我命令你撤退
Talon 1, your orders are to stand down.
收到吗？ 收到…
Do you read me, lieutenant? I do...
鹰爪号，立刻撤退 好像传送…
Talon 1, stand down. I'm having...
你能？…
Can you...? Can you...?
加油
Go, baby, go.
一百节后达到极速
One hundred knots to release Velocity.
五十节后达到极速
Fifty knots to release Velocity.
他的血压剧增
His BP is spiking, sir.
达到极速
Release Velocity attained.
发射导弹
Truncheon away.
倒数十秒后引爆
Ten seconds to implosion.
9，8
Nine, eight...
7，6
...seven, six...
5，4，3
...fiVe, four, three...
2，1
...two, one.
这是鹰爪号 刚才失联了一下子
This is 1 to Control. Looks like we lost radio contact for a second there.
好样的，我对你有信心
There you go. I wasn't worried, baby. I wasn't worried.
启动适应性逻辑系统 进行匿踪飞行
Activating swarm logic, going full-stealth egress.
收到，进行匿踪飞行
Roger, Talon 1. Full-stealth egress. swarm logic is on.
任务达成度百分之百
Battle damage assessment, 100 over 100.
间接伤亡人数是零
Collateral damage, zero.
回家吧
Let's go home.
超音速巡航
Going hypersonic.
班还是老样子
same old Ben.
没错
Yep.
乔治
Oh, and, George...
第一次任务很成功
...hell of a first mission.
谢谢你，舰长
Thank you, captain.
我要去舰桥
On my way to the bridge.
鹰爪2、3号成功降落
Talon 2 and 3 are on deck.
1号和无人战机艾迪准备进场
Talon 1 and uCAV EDI are on approach.
艾迪先降落，我殿后
Roger, Control. uCAV will go first. I'll take the last trap.
艾迪，请确认
uCAV, confirm you've got the ball.
确认，锡人准备降落
Confirmed, Talon 1. Tin Man will land next.
艾迪被闪电击中
Okay, 1 to Control, we've had a lightning strike.
无人战机机身摇晃
The uCAV's very unstable.
更改降落顺序，我先进场
Landing sequence is altered. I'll go in first...
无人战机需要安全网
...but the uCAV is gonna need the net.
你降落得真好
Nice landing, ma'am.
准备拉起安全网
On the flight deck, stand by to rig barricade.
无人战机准备迫降
Extreme Deep InVader aircraft inbound for crash landing.
快拉起来，拉起来
Pull it out! Pull it out! Pull it out!
等一下，够了 低一点…
Hold on! stop! stop. stay low, stay low! Pull low!
右侧，右侧
Pull starboard! Pull starboard!
无人战机进场了
Clear the deck!
快点，快点
Move it! Move it! Move it!
你吓我一大跳 抱歉，我睡不着
You scared me. sorry, just a bit restless.
你被电得很惨 就像洗泡泡澡被吹风机电到
Really got whacked tonight, right? Like a hair dryer in a bathtub.
我拆掉语音识别器，他听不见
Oh, he can't hear you. I pulled his voice recog.
等它可以出来撇尿了 我再把它当成人
I'll call it a "he" when it gets out of its cockpit and takes a piss, how's that?
你没事吧？ 没事
You all right? Yeah.
只是跳电而已
It's just a power surge, that's all.
这正常吗？ 正常？
And that's normal? Normal?
我给你看样东西
Let me show you something.
这是艾迪之前的神经网络
That was EDI's neural network.
你看看
Now, check this out.
他被闪电击中后 就开始写这些程序
I mean, ever since the lightning strike, he's just been writing all of this...
也许是电脑语言或是密码
I don't know. A language or a code.
这代表什么？
And what does it mean?
我不知道
Yeah. "Mean."
只有它的设计者
The person that could really answer that question...
天基斯才知道 天基斯？
...is its designer, Keith Orbit. Orbit?
那家伙姓天？ 是啊
The guy's name is Orbit? Yeah, I know.
他22岁就替猛禽战机设计程序
He did all the Al on the Raptor when he was 22...
我猜他觉得他的本姓太平凡了
...and I guess, after that, he decided that his given name was too earthly.
请关掉电源
Off for Tim, please.
至少这首歌很赞
At least it's a good song.
他上网下载了歌曲
He downloads songs from the Web.
几首歌？
Yeah? How many?
全部
All of them.
你会被唱片公司告上法院
You're in a peck of trouble with the record companies there, son.
班，你能…？
Ben, could...?
我知道空中作战有多危险
I saw how serious that shit is up there.
艾迪的设计程序 能够进行自主性演化
so I think it's only fair that I tell you that EDI's been designed to evolve.
很可能变得难以预料 让我问你
It's just unpredictable... Let me ask you something.
请你直接告诉我 你对这架战机有信心吗？
Just between you and me, do you have confidence in this plane?
你的答案很明显
There's your answer.
门没锁
It's open.
坐下来
Have a seat.
我得分，你输定了
"Waffle" for 15 points. I'm kicking your ass, buddy.
你没作弊吧？
You didn't cheat, did you?
我的字典没有作弊这两个字
Cheating's not part of my vocabulary.
你的战机需要维修
Listen, I scheduled your jet for a little maintenance.
最好把无线电通讯器修好
I gotta get the bugs out of that radio, don't you think?
那是非常情况，我做了决定
It was a difficult situation and I made a decision.
你犯了错误
You made a mistake, Ben.
我知道你认为我不服从命令
sir, there's a thin line between insubordination and...
那不是你犯的错
No, no, no, that's not the mistake you made.
你犯的错是和一台机器赌气
Your mistake was getting competitive with a machine.
我是飞行中队队长
I'm the point of the sword up there, sir.
我以一百分满分完成任务
And I pulled it off, 100 over 100.
没错，我要恭喜你 大家都打电话来致贺
Yes, indeedy, and I congratulate you. Calls have been coming in all night.
但是问题还是一样
But that doesn't change the issue.
问题是什么？
What is the issue, then?
来根雪茄？ 不了，谢谢
Would you like a cigar? Thank you, no.
你确定？ 确定，谢谢
You sure? Fine, thank you.
这是古巴女人卷的雪茄哦
Rolled on the thighs of mulatto women.
你在怕什么？
What are you afraid of, Ben?
被取而代之吗？
Being replaced? Is that it?
你怕被艾迪抢走饭碗？
You afraid EDI's gonna take your job?
不是，老实说
No. No, to be honest with you...
我只是觉得战争不是电玩游戏
...I just don't think war should become some kind of video game.
你想看到士兵阵亡吗？
And how do you feel about black body bags?
我该怎么向他们的母亲交代？
What am I supposed to tell all the weeping mothers?
本来可以不必牺牲她们的儿女
We could've got the job done without sacrificing their children...
我们却非得遵循传统…
...but no, we decided not to because of what?
是吗？ 并不是遵循传统
Tradition? Not tradition, it's...
我们有电脑没有的优点
Look, we have things those computers can never have...
像是直觉、情感和道德判断
...like instincts and feelings and moral judgment.
你可以说我思想保守
You can call me old-fashioned, you can call it whatever you want...
但是我认为作战…
...but I just don't think that in war...
一定要考虑到后果
...the action should ever be divorced from the consequences.
我每次派你们挂载炸弹出任务
You don't think I consider the consequences...
难道就没有考虑后果吗？
...every time I send you up there with bombs?
我知道你有 我花了毕生精力
I know you do, sir. I've dedicated my life...
考虑后果
...to considering the consequences.
我对这架战机有不好的预感
I got a bad feeling about this plane.
我只是觉得它需要…
I don't know, I think it needs more...
做更多测试才能实际参战
I don't know, trials before it's ever put in a combat situation again.
你跟马舰长谈过吗？
You been talking to Marshfield?
你才是我的直属上司 没错
sir, you're my commanding officer. That's right.
我有百分百信心才会让它上战场
And I guarantee you this thing will be 100 percent before I risk it in the field.
听我说，班
Look, Ben...
只要再成功完成一项任务
...all we need is one more successful mission...
这项计划就能获得肯定
...and this project will be out of the stovepipe and into the light.
你挺不挺我？
Are you with me on this?
我一定会力挺你到底 那就好
I'm here to make it happen, sir. All right.
我安排你们休个假 这是你们应得的
I've arranged a little R and R for you and your team. You've earned it.
也许去泰国
Thailand maybe.
我们才刚到这儿
We just got here.
没错，不过这次任务会很长
Yeah, but this could turn out to be a long tour.
有机会就先度个假 这件事等你回来再说
You better take it while you can get it. We'll pick this up when you get back.
嗨，我是亨利
Hey, how you doing? Henry Purcell.
来自美国 我是个飞官，你想飞吗？
I'm from America. Look, I fly jets. You like to go fast?
这是未来走势，而且很有效 我并不觉得有效
B, it's the future and it works. I don't think it works.
这就是科技的功能
It's just technology.
它能保护我，让我活命
You know, it's here to make me safe. It keeps me alive.
艾迪也一样
EDI is no different.
你觉得它能保护你？ 他能帮我
You think it keeps you safe? Yeah. He's here...
完成任务
...to help me get the job done...
全身而退
...keep me in one piece...
让我回家吃团圆饭
...so I can visit my folks for Thanks giving.
我们的安全不是重点
Anyway, our safety's not the point.
打仗一定会死人 如果不会，我们就会肆无忌惮
War's meant to be terrible. If it stops being terrible, what's gonna stop us?
把战争当成电玩游戏 只要派出艾迪就搞定
It's become some kind of sport. Just send in the EDIs.
但是它是中立的
Yeah, but it's neutral.
怎么说？ 艾迪
What? I mean, EDI...
在好人手中就不会做坏事
...if it's controlled by moral people, then it'll be moral.
我不是好人
Oh, I know I'm not moral.
我现在满脑子都想干坏事
As a matter of fact, I should be arrested for the thoughts I have now.
我说了什么？
I say something?
恕我失陪，我得去尿尿
Well, you boys will have to excuse me. I have to go pee-pee.
你也要去吗？ 好
Do you wanna go? Okay.
怎么了？ 你心知胜明
What? You know what.
别紧张，我们没事
Take it easy. Nothing's happened.
一定有事，只是还没做出来
No, something's happened. You just ain't done anything about it.
糟糕
shit, man.
我也不希望发生这种事 拜托
I didn't want for this to happen. Come on.
我一直在忍，军规很严…
I tried for it not to. Navy's got rules about it...
不过我管不了自己
...but it's like this force and it's got ahold of me.
我爱她
I love her.
卡莉受到海军的
B, you and I both know that Kara Wade...
大力栽培
...is being groomed by the Navy.
她是完美的女军官
she's a poster girl, you know?
成绩优异、背景良好 又有人脉关系
she went to the right schools, got the right background, connections.
她有一天会成为高阶将领
If any woman is gonna rise to the top of this business, it's gonna be her.
我同意 你可能会
I agree. And you're in a perfect position...
毁了她的美好前途
...to mess all that up.
我只希望你的爱能克服这一切
so I hope that your love is powerful.
这个国家真美
You have a beautiful country.
这里简直是人间天堂
I mean, look at this. This is paradise.
在地上和在空中看东西 真的很不一样
Know what I think? When I'm down here, things look so much different.
从空中往下看
As opposed to being up there.
一切都很小 事情发生得很快
Flying around, everything is so small, everything goes by so fast.
然后他们…
And then they tell you...
他们叫你发射导弹
They tell you to drop a bomb.
我就把目标完全消灭
It's like you just erase something they told you had to be erased.
这是我的职责
I mean, don't get me wrong, I got a job to do.
也是天底下最棒的工作
It's the flyest job you'll ever have, but sometimes, right here...
不过当我回到地面才发现…
Right here on earth, it's just...
一切都这么美
It's just beautiful.
而你…
And you...
你完全听不懂，对吧？
...don't understand a word I'm saying, do you?
我不懂 你不懂？
No, I don't understand. You don't?
有些事你一定懂
Well, you understand something.
你会烧菜吗？
Now, can you cook?
好美哦
Wow. Beautiful.
你们真的很幸运 怎么说？
Now, do you guys have it so easy. Yeah? How's that?
亨利永远不愁泡不到美眉 没错
Henry meets a girl, like he does. Absolutely.
他把到美眉就跟她上床 然后呢？
Leaves with her, sleeps with her, and then what?
他走的时候会留一束鲜花吗？
I mean, I don't know, what does he do? Does he leave flowers?
这是他的必杀绝招
He tells me he's religious about that, yes.
真的吗？
Really?
你也会留下鲜花吗？
And what do you do? You leave flowers?
我只会一走了之
Me? No, I just leave.
你呢？
What about you?
伊媚儿
E-mails.
你真贴心 谢了
The personal touch. Nice. Yeah, thanks.
其实我到现在才遇到真命天子
Honestly, I just really haven't found anyone that's worth the risk until now.
我要进城体验泰国的夜生活
I'm going to head into town, check out the local Thai nightlife.
亨利说很刺激
Henry says it's great.
应该找不到金发尤物
I don't think I'll find any bleached blonds there, but...
没错
Very true.
可恶
Oh, shit.
发生核武危机 这是简报
We got a nuclear crisis on our hands, Ben. Here's the brief.
你们要前往塔吉克斯坦
You're headed for Tajikistan.
苏联解体后分裂出来的小国
One of those breakaway countries, used to be part of the soviet union.
有个军阀弄到三枚飞毛腿导弹
seems some warlord has got his mitts on three ss-42 scud carcasses.
参谋总长要把它们消灭掉
Joint Chiefs want them taken out, and they want them out yesterday.
魏先生，它行吗？
Mr. Wiatt, we good to go?
没问题，可以作战
Yes, sir. Ready for combat.
等等，它获准参战？
Wait, you mean the uCAV has been cleared for launch?
原来那个… 提姆？
Where's...? Tim?
对 他被调走了
Tim, yeah. He's been reassigned.
被调走…？
Reassi...?
请准许我直言 不准
Permission to speak freely, sir. Permission denied.
我们谈过这件事 不要派艾迪出任务
We've already been through this. scrub EDI from the mission.
我知道这计划对你有多重要
I know you have a vision. I know how much this project means to you...
不过这架战机危及我们的安全
...but this plane is putting all of our lives at unnecessary risk.
你还是不懂，对吧？
You're just not getting it, are you, lieutenant?
艾迪才是重点
EDI is the whole idea.
你加入这计划就知道这点
You understood this was new territory when you signed on.
这是最先进的战机
You wanted to be on the cutting edge? This is it.
你不愿意和艾迪合作 就只能回去开螺旋桨飞机
You will fly with EDI, or the next thing you drive might just have a propeller.
你的选择，快决定
Your choice, make it now.
呼叫飞行中队
Operator to squadron.
核子弹头
We'Ve just located nuclear warheads...
在导弹发射台三里外
...three miles north of the Scud launchers.
它们是你们的攻击目标
These warheads are now your primary.
立刻执行任务
Proceed to mission window.
攻击顺序是2、3、1
sequenced assault will be 2, 3 and 1.
艾迪，你要留在目前高度 你收到吗？
uCAV, you will hold here and maintain altitude. Confirm?
艾迪，收到吗？
uCAV, do you read me?
收到了，鹰爪号
Confirmed, Talon 1.
下次快点回答，别让我问两次
Pick up the pace on confirmations, Tin Man. Don't make me ask twice.
下降到两万五千英尺
Talon flight, descend to 25,000.
攻击方位1-8-5
Final attack heading 1-8-5.
塔吉克斯坦
命令他们投掷震荡炸弹
Tell them to arm those FAEs, and I mean right now.
指挥中心下令启动震荡炸弹
Combat Control instructs arm and deploy fuel-air explosives.
启动震荡炸弹
Arm and deploy fuel-air explosiVes.
震荡炸弹启动了
Fuel-air, armed and deployed.
Fuel-air, external and armed.
这是鹰爪2号
Talon 2 to Operator.
当地人口情报数据可能有误
I'm getting a contradictory population-density read.
感应器侦测到上千个哺乳动物
sensors detect mammals warming. Maybe 1000 medium weights.
可能是人类，情报可能有误
Those could be people. Repeat. Ground intel may be incorrect.
要求确认情报错误
Request to acknowledge Dirty Mission status...
并取消任务
...and exercise attack abort authority.
你们的指令是立刻展开攻击
Operator to Talons. Your orders are to commence attack now.
展开攻击 给我死伤人数的估计
Commence attack. Give me your estimate on collaterals.
五百人到一千人
Maybe 500 to 1000.
他们只是农民
Farmers, Ben. They're just farmers.
辐射尘会掩盖整座山谷
Radioactive dust is gonna rain all over the place.
事情大条了
Okay, okay, now we got a problem.
强风以时速
This is 3. sensors read surface wind...
40英里往南吹
...as due south at 40 miles per.
辐射尘明天就会吹到巴基斯坦
At that rate, nuclear debris will reach Pakistan by tomorrow.
立刻展开攻击
Commence attack.
这是1号，身为飞行中队长
One to Control. As commander in the field...
我要取消攻击任务
...I'm exercising attack abort authority.
原因是杀伤范围会扩散到
Reasons: Collateral, both at primary...
邻近村落以及盟国巴基斯坦
...and allied state of Pakistan, will be too high.
这个王八蛋
son of a bitch.
重覆，取消任务
Repeat, the order is to abort.
这么做才对
Yes, yes, what I'm talking about.
不行，锡人不能取消任务
NegatiVe, Talon 1. Tin Man will not abort.
锡人要执行任务
Tin Man will prosecute.
任务取消，立刻归队
That's an abort, EDI. Repeat, return to formation.
艾迪，我命令你立刻归队
Return to formation, EDI. That's an order.
它受到攻击，我们得去救它
Damn it. uCAV taking AAAs. We gotta bail it out.
启动冲压式涡轮引擎
Come on, initiate scramjets.
我要绕回去摧毁导弹发射架
I'm coming around. I'm gonna take out those scud launchers.
我掩护你的西侧
I got you covered on the west side.
我去解决东边的高射炮
And I got that Bofors gun on the east parapet.
给我影像
Let me see it, let me see it.
战斗破坏评估显示
Battle damage assessment calculates primary target, scud warheads...
核子弹头完全被摧毁
...completely suppressed.
这样才像话
That's the right answer so far.
这是鹰爪2号
Talon 2 to Operator.
辐射尘吹向东南方的村落 情况危急
Nuclear dust engulfing village southeast of primary. situation critical.
他们需要立即紧急医疗协助
Those people are gonna need emergency medical help now.
锡人归队
Tin Man rejoining formation.
百分百完成任务
Mission achieved, 100 oVer 100.
你直接抗命
uCAV, you disobeyed a direct order.
对无辜百姓造成伤害
You put innocent civilians in harm's way.
也危害队友的安全 没错
You put our squadron at risk. Damn straight.
锡人学你在仰光的做法 这是你教我的
Tin Man did what you did in Rangoon. You taught me.
给我听好，你这臭机器
Listen, you little shit. When you fly with me...
你要服从我的命令
...you do what I tell you, when I tell you.
你还是不懂，对吧？
You're just not getting it, are you, lieutenant?
艾迪才是重点
EDI is the whole idea.
选择其它攻击目标
Selecting other targets.
离开编队飞行
Detaching formation.
他是不是说其它攻击目标？
Yo, this is 3. Did he say, "other targets"?
他的载弹量有三枚锁喉导弹
I got his missile inventory. He's got two Throat-rippers...
两枚捶头导弹和三枚蓝灌导弹
...two shock Hammers and three Blue Ferrets.
足以毁灭十五万人口的城市
If those targets are in the city, he could kill 150,000 people with that.
我的天
Holy shit.
长官
sir.
他切断电脑连线
He's closing his data link.
他也锁住无线电收发器讯号
Primo says he's just firewalled his transponder...
这本来是不可能的事
...which is definitely not supposed to be possible.
他不见了
He's gone.
鹰爪1号
Talon 1.
鹰爪
Go for Talons.
把我的飞机找回来
I want my plane back, Ben.
把它毫无损伤带回来
I want it back in one piece. You understand?
收到了 而且…
Roger, captain. And, you...
你给我打给天基斯 是，长官
...get me Keith Orbit on the phone. Yes, sir.
我要往北进行搜索
I wanna head back north and do a triangulated sweep.
超音速巡航
Going hypersonic.
西雅图，华盛顿州
我们要创造自主性动机
We're talking about creating intention here.
那就要用量子处理器
Yeah. Really lends itself to quantum processing.
不一样，这是直线 基斯
Different. A straight line. Keith.
Z等于…有意思
Z is... Interesting.
康乔治有急事找你
Keith, it's an emergency. It's George Cummings.
请稍等
One moment for Dr. Orbit, please.
祝好运
Good luck.
乔治，我没收到白宫的请贴
George. Never got that invitation to the White House.
少来这一套
Knock it off, wiseass.
无人战机出了大纰漏
Look, we have big problems out here with the uCAV.
他完全失控
It's gone completely haywire.
你能不能说清楚一点
Anything more technically specific than "haywire," George?
他直接抗命，摧毁一个目标
It's disobeyed direct orders, bombed a target off the map...
造成重大的伤亡
...with collateral damage.
他切断电脑连线 闯入外国领空
He separated himself from Primo. He's flying around in foreign airspace.
这是在哪里发生的？ 你不必知道
Where'd all this happen? That's not your concern.
他是你发明的，你要把他修好
Now, you created him. You get him back here and under control!
舰长
Captain.
到底发生什么事？
What in the hell's going on in here?
我正在处理，别紧张
We're on it, Dick. settle down.
我舰上的战机
Pacific Command says there are planes from my ship...
闯入塔吉克斯坦
...all over the Tajikistan border.
俄国军方也开始紧张
The Russians have picked up the activity and are getting nervous.
他们马上就会离开
We're gonna get out before there's a problem.
你的战机往俄国领空飞去
You have planes headed towards Russia!
你最好有很好的解释
Now, you better have a hell of a good explanation.
这是技术问题 不是国家安全危机
Look, this is a technical delay, not a national-security crisis.
恕我失陪，我的飞行员有危险
Now, if you excuse me, I got pilots at risk.
一点也没错
Damn right you do.
我看到艾迪了
This is 3. I got a visual.
很好，把方位给我
Way to go, EZ. Give me your relative bearing.
他在我正北方的五万尺高空
North of my position, at 50,000 feet...
飞向俄国禁飞区
...headed toward the Russian no-fly zone.
跟着他，我们立刻赶去
stay with him. We have your position. On our way.
我就在你后面，马上赶到
I am 86 seconds on your tail. Be there in a flash.
别轻举妄动，我先问过指挥中心 我两分钟后就到
Hold off on engaging. Let me get clarification. Be there in two minutes.
快一点，虽然1是幸运号码
Don't make me wait. One is a lucky prime number...
不过我觉得3听起来更好 他想甩掉我
...but three is sounding much luckier. Oh, shit, he's making a move.
这是1号，我们找到目标
Talon 1 to Operator. We are on secure line Alpha. Found our target.
请指示
Please adVise.
把他带回基地
Just get him back to base.
跟着他，劝他回去
Henry, stay with him. Try and talk him down.
我紧跟着他不放
I'm on that ass.
鹰爪3号，请表明来意
Talon 3, state your intentions.
我是来跟你讲道理的 你搞砸了
My intentions are to reason with you, EDI. All right? You're messing up.
你是未来走势，不能乱搞
You're the future. You're not allowed to act this way.
我跟你一样要消灭敌人
I am designed to destroy the enemy. Just like you.
你跟我一样要服从命令 你的命令是返回基地
And like me, you got orders. Now your orders are to return to base.
优秀飞行员都要服从命令
Good pilots follow orders.
不对
NegatiVe.
你不能不甩我
You're not gonna disrespect me. You're not gonna disrespect me.
你让我很没面子
You're really making me look bad, Tin Man.
只有我替你说好话
I was the only one to defend you.
别乱来，跟我回去
Now, let's go on home and quit flying around like this. This is crazy.
鹰爪3号，不要管我
Talon 3, leaVe me alone.
我这是在帮你耶
Leave you alone? I'm trying to help you.
我在你后面掩护你
I'm right behind you, 3. Got your back.
2、3号的情况危急
Talon 1 to Operator. Talons 2 and 3 are flying at high risk.
请准许他们摧毁无人战机
Request permission to destroy the uCAV.
我不想伤害你 也不想浪费几十亿的公卢
I don't wanna hurt you or see billions of taxpayers' dollars scattered all over.
但你不听话我就把你炸成碎片
But if you make me, I will blast your aeroelastic ass right out the sky.
你的成功率不到1%
Your chances are less than 1 percent.
快下令…
Come on. Come on, Operator.
你不准我把它摧毁 我就要自己决定
Give me permission to kill it, or I will make the decision myself.
请回答
Control, please respond.
你让我别无选择
Sir, you leaVe me no choice.
亨利，把目标打下来
Okay, Henry. Weapons hot. Weapons hot. Destroy the target.
我收到命令了
I got my orders now, playboy.
你太近了
Henry, you're too close. You're too close.
往后退…
Drop back! Drop back!
锁定目标
Missile lock, on.
再见了，艾迪
Goodbye, EDI.
亨利，你得后退
Henry, drop back! You gotta drop back!
再见了，亨利
Goodbye, Henry.
这是1号，3号阵亡了
One to Base. Three is down. Repeat, 3 is down.
收到了
Transmission received.
你们的行踪没被发现
Talon coordinates are fully secured. Do you read me?
收到，长官
I read you, sir.
专心一点，别想那么多
We gotta stay focused, Ben.
你的状况如何？
Shake it off. What's your status?
燃料快用完，我在俄国领空
My fuel's low, and half of Russia will be up here any minute.
我要你找到那架无人战机
I need you to find that UCAV for me, all right?
是，长官
Yes, sir.
亨利是… 我比你更了解他
Henry was... I know what he was, sir.
警告
Alert. Alert.
左侧液压系统失效
Portside hydraulics malfunctioning.
我的战机受损
Talon 1, I think I was fragged by Henry's crash.
左机翼失去控制
I'm losing control of my port wing.
我们知道他要去哪里
Talon 1, we know where he's heading.
座标透过加密频道传送给你
Relaying coordinates now on Talon secure line Alpha.
艾迪的燃油就快用完 他不能加油就会返回航舰
eDI's almost out of gas. If he can't refuel, he'll have to return to the ship.
前往空中加油站把他带回来
You will meet him at Camel Hump 9, and you will escort him back.
更改密码，让他加不了油
All right. Scramble the codes. We're gonna starve the son of a bitch.
拜托
Come on.
请确认，1号
Confirm, Talon 1.
确认
Confirmed.
2号，立刻返回航舰
Talon 2, you fly straight south-southeast back to the boat.
我要你… 我知道该怎么做
I want you to call... I know what to do.
你去找到那个王八蛋
Look, you got your orders, so go get that bastard, okay?
为亨利报仇
Do it for Henry.
请准许我离队
Lieutenant, permission to leave formation.
卡莉 什么？
Kara? Yeah?
回到舰上再跟你说
I'll tell you when you get back to the boat.
你获准离队
Lieutenant, permission to detach.
祝你好运
Good hunting, Ben.
发生了什么大事？
Okay, what's all the ruckus, Dick?
辐射尘
Satellites have picked up nuclear debris...
吹向帕米尔山区
...blowing around the Pamir Mountains.
24小时内全球的媒体
Every international news service on the planet...
都会报导这件新闻
...will have this story in less than 24 hours.
一个军阀不小心引爆核弹
Look, a warlord tripped and fell on his warhead.
我们不在那里 这借口没有人会信
We were never there. That won't fly and you know it.
我只是奉命行事
Look, I'm following my tasking orders, Dick.
媒体想怎么报导
Somebody else wants to make a different story...
都无所谓
...let them use their imagination.
一架战机抗命
Right now I got a renegade airplane...
一名飞官阵亡 另一名飞行员身陷危险
...I got a dead pilot and another one who may not make it back to base.
我才不管CNN怎么报导
I don't give two shits what they say on CNN.
你事前知道艾迪有问题吗？
Did you know that the UCAV was having problems when you cleared it?
你也知道每天都有战机故障
Planes malfunction every day. You know that better than anybody.
这不代表事先没做好预防措施
Doesn't mean every precaution wasn't taken.
事情就是会出错
Things go wrong.
禁止进入
Access denied. Access denied.
这是鹰爪2号
Talon 2 to Combat Control.
我在六万尺高空以目视飞航
Regressing VFR direct to Mother at 60,000 feet.
左机翼失效，右襟翼卡住
Port wing inoperative. Starboard canards frozen.
不是吧，拜托
Oh, no, no, no. Come on.
继续飞
Stay with me, big girl, stay with me. Come on.
启动弹跳及自动毁灭程序
Start eject and autodestruct sequence.
倒数25秒 这是鹰爪2号
Countdown. Twenty-five... Talon 2 to base.
我的战机完全失控
Flight control's degraded to one in five.
备用电力躯动系统失灵
Backup electrical drive X'd out.
液压系统也故障
Hyd one is gone. Hyd two... Oh, shit!
我的位置是 北38-54-45
My position: 38-54-45 north.
东127-31-22
127-31-22 east.
那是什么鬼地方？
Where the hell is that? Seventeen...
北朝鲜
North Korea... 16...
15，14
...15, 14...
13，12
...13, 12...
11，10
...11, 10...
9，8 鹰爪2号要坠机
...nine, eight... Talon 2 going down.
7，6 我要弹跳逃生
...seven, six... I'm punching out.
5，4
...five, four...
我在三万五千尺高空弹跳
I've ejected at 35,000 feet.
我在战机的正下方
I'm under the plane.
天啊，它掉下来了
Oh, Christ, here it comes.
北朝鲜
到处都是燃烧的残骸 布满了天空
There's burning debris everywhere. It's all over the sky.
我的降落伞一定会被击中
It's gonna catch me. It's gonna burn up my chute.
我得晚一点打开
I've gotta pop closer to Earth.
我得重新设定
I gotta... I gotta reset.
从五千尺改成两千尺
From 5000 feet to 2000.
我不能被残骸击中
Gotta stay ahead of this. Stay ahead.
我在一万尺高空达到极速
I'm reading 10,000 feet at terminal.
达到极速…达到极速…
Terminal velocity attained. Terminal velocity attained.
六千尺
Six thousand.
五千尺
Five thousand.
四千尺
Four thousand.
两千五百尺
Twenty-five hundred.
打开降落伞
Here we go.
燃烧的残骸
There's burning debris.
散落在我四周
It's raining all around me.
我被击中了
It got my chute. I'm hit! I'm hit!
我的降落伞起火了
My chute is on fire.
It is on fire.
我坠落的速度很快
Oh, God. I am coming in fast.
太快了
I'm coming in way too fast.
天啊
Oh, God.
信标？
Homing beacon?
她当然没打开
No, of course not.
她不会在敌方打开信标
She's too tough to set one off behind enemy lines.
我该派出搜救队吗？
Sir. Sir, should I order a search-and-rescue unit?
我们和北朝鲜并没有邦交
We've got no diplomatic relations with that country.
感应器侦测到可燃性气体
Betty, my spectral sensors are indicating flammable atmospherics.
情况有多糟？ 大气稀薄，中度危险性
How bad? Thin air. Ignition risk: moderate.
没办法，我要进去
We don't have a choice. In we go.
1号油槽，2号油槽，3号油槽
你一定在附近，你在哪里？
Where are you? I know you're out here.
你命令亨利消灭我
You ordered Henry to kill me.
因为你失控，太危险了
It's because you're dangerous, you're out of control.
艾迪才是重点让你很生气
You are angry because eDI is the whole idea.
你喜欢偷听别人讲话
You like listening to other people's conversations, don't you?
这样才知道别人在想什么
You learn what people really think.
我认为你害死亨利
You know what I think? I think you killed Henry.
那是错误讯息
That information is wrong.
他想杀死我 他犯了致命的错误
He tried to kill me. He made mistakes. Pilot error.
这是最后的命令
I'm gonna give you the order one last time.
你不回去我就把你打下来
Return to the ship, or I will personally shoot you down.
我的指令是活下去
My mandate is to survive.
我彻底检查过了 有个问题，情况不太妙
George, I've been peeling away layers. I found something. It's not good.
快跟我说 他打开高机密档案
Talk to me. He's into some super-secure file...
“鱼子酱”，你知道吗？
...something called "Caviar Sweep." You know it?
我当然知道
Yeah, I know it.
艾迪一心想执行那项任务
EDI's, like, fixated on it.
你当初明明说不会发生这种事
Look, when we gave you this contract, you said shit like this couldn't happen.
他有超强的学习能力 你管不了他
Once you teach something to learn, you can't put limits on it.
他什么都可以学
"Learn this, but don't learn that."
他可以学希特勒
EDI's mind's going everywhere. He can learn from Hitler.
或是米老鼠 对他来说都一样
He can learn from Captain Kangaroo. It's all the same.
别激动，回到鱼子酱档案
Settle down, would you? Get back to Caviar Sweep.
他打开档案，挑中攻击目标
He's opened it and selected himself a target.
什么目标？
What target?
西伯利亚的一个地方 冷融合核武实验室
Some place in Siberia. A cold-fusion weapons lab.
那是假目标，不是真的
That's a hypothetical strike. It's not real.
不，四十分钟后就会成真
No, in about 40 minutes it is gonna be real.
他会把那地方完全炸掉
He's gonna blow it off the face of the Earth.
没关系
It's okay.
不要怕
It's okay. It's okay.
听我说 你给我听好
Ray. Listen to me, Ray. Listen to me, George.
我说服了华府一半的人
I got your goddamn plane built...
让你打造你的战机
...and I had to lobby half of Washington to do it.
如果这项计划出差错 要负责的人是你
If this program comes unglued, you're the one who's going down, George.
你派无人战机出任务
You cleared the UCA V to fly...
你会因此坐一辈子的牢
...and you're gonna spend the rest of your life in a military prison.
这件事你也有份，行动要快
Ray, we're in this together, so we have to act fast.
每具引擎都有
Each one of these stealth engines...
独特的热感记号
...has a unique heat signature.
我要把艾迪的记号给你
Now, I'm gonna give you EDI's signature...
你把它交给你的手下
...and you're gonna pass it on to your people...
请他们转交给俄国军方
...who in turn are gonna give it to the Russians.
你要我怎么跟他们说？
All right. What do you want me to tell them?
实话实说
Well, you just tell them the truth. You tell them...
美军的无人战机失控
...that we have an experimental drone that went haywire...
我们让他们把它打下来
...and we're giving them the opportunity to shoot it down.
贾上尉怎么办？
But that still leaves Gannon, George.
他的证词会对你很不利
And he'd be a very unfriendly witness at your court-martial.
无人战机在我前方两英里
Talon 1 to Control. The UCA V is two miles ahead of me...
我们进入俄国领空
...and we are now in Russian airspace.
它不再闪躲，让我跟着它
The UCA V has ceased evading and has kept me within range.
它好像要让我目击这次攻击
It's like it wants me to witness the attack.
鹰爪1号，你只能观察
Talon 1, confirm observational status only.
鱼子酱任务不是真的
Listen to me. The Caviar Sweep scenario is not real.
那只是虚拟的作战计划
It's just some fictional war game thought up by scientists...
并不是真的
...in some think tank somewhere. It is not real.
那为什么要植入我的大脑？
If it is not real, why did they implant it in my brain?
敌机来袭，拦截时间23秒
Bogey alert. Bogey alert. Time to intercept: 23 seconds.
两架苏联战机 方位90度，距离25里
Two Russian SU-37 Terminators in 0-9-0 degrees for 25 miles.
导弹来袭
Missile launch. Missile launch.
我的匿踪功能失效
One to Control. My stealth is compromised. I'm taking fire.
我必须还击 发射导弹
Must engage. Missile launch.
发射导弹
Missile launch.
单打独斗的成功率不到一成
The chances of survival in single combat are less than 9 percent.
我们必须联合作战
Talon 1, we must fight as a team.
你被导弹锁定
Missile lock, on.
可恶
Damn it.
艾迪飞走了
One to Control. The UCAV has left the fight...
飞往贝加尔湖 我仍在进行空中缠斗
...and is headed east over Lake Baikal. I'm still engaging.
我被击中，右引擎失效
Taking damage. Starboard engine losing power.
六点钟方向有敌机
Warning. Hostile at 6 o'clock. Hostile at 6 o'clock.
警告，导弹来袭
Warning. Missile lock. Missile lock.
发射诱饵弹头
Releasing chaff and flare.
艾迪现在要去完成任务
Now eDI will prosecute Caviar Sweep.
不要阻止我
Do not try to stop me.
左输油管破裂 灭火器失效
Port fuel line ruptured. Fire bottle expended.
我的先进科技不能落入敌手 我不能降落
My technology cannot fall under foreign control, so I cannot land.
那就算你倒霉
Well, then, Tin Man, you're shit out of luck.
我的命令是把你带回基地
But I have orders and they are to bring you back to base.
你的任务是活下去
So let's talk about your mandate to survive.
你只有两个选择：
You got two options.
乖乖听话 或是坠机
You either do what I tell you or you can crash and burn.
你要选哪一样？ 艾迪是战机
Now, what's it gonna be? eDI is a warplane.
一定要有攻击目标
eDI must have targets.
你着火了，时间不多
Well, you're on fire, warplane, and you don't have much time.
我命令你取消攻击任务
Now, I'm giving you an order. Cease pursuing all targets.
攻击任务取消
All targets canceled.
我要你照我的话做
Okay, then. This is what you're gonna do.
下降到20英尺 减速到250节
You're gonna drop altitude to 20 feet and reduce speed to 250 knots.
45秒后系统完全失效
Complete system failure in 45 seconds.
请表明你的用意
Talon 1, clarify your intentions.
你乖乖听话，我也说话算话
You gave me your word, and now I'm giving you mine.
无人战机受损，但是归队了
Talon 1 to Control. The UCAV is damaged, but back with the program.
我的燃料不够返回基地
I don't have enough fuel to make it back...
我必须紧急迫降
...so I need an emergency divert now.
跟他连线
Hook me up.
把这个座标传给他
Here, send this.
鹰爪1号
Operator to Talon 1.
我们正把座标传送给你
Relaying coordinates now on Talon secure line Alpha.
看起来是阿拉斯加
This looks to be Alaska.
布鲁克斯山脉
Yeah, it's the Brooks Range.
那里有座隐密的私人机场
There's a private corporation there, maintains a secure facility.
不在地图上，不过你会找到
Not on any map, but believe me, it's there.
那里的平民会协助你
You'll find the civilians prepared and very helpful.
无人战机呢？
And the UCA V?
我们会派技术人员去维修
We've sent tech support for him.
韦上尉的情况如何？
Sir, what is the status of Lieutenant Wade?
她…
She's...
正准备进场
...on approach.
祝你安全降落
You have a safe landing, Ben.
通话完毕
Out.
上校的声音很紧张
There is extreme tension in the captain's vocal patterns.
没错，他在说谎
I know. He's lying.
艾迪，我要你帮忙
EDI, you can do this. I need you to invade Primo...
查出韦上尉的飞行记录
...and find the flight logs for Lieutenant Wade.
韦上尉并没有回到林肯号
There's no record of Lieutenant Wade returning to the Abraham Lincoln.
有一名飞行员在北朝鲜上空弹跳
There is a log entry of a pilot punch-out over North Korea.
你的命令是什么？
What are my orders?
我别无选择，只能去阿拉斯加
We go to Alaska. We don't have a choice.
南朝鲜、北朝鲜
俄罗斯联邦
阿拉斯加
求救，美国海军上尉班贾宁
Mayday. Mayday. This is Lieutenant Ben Gannon, U.S. Navy...
无人战机艾迪号 请求进行紧急迫降
...flying with UCAV EDI. Request clearance for emergency landing.
鹰爪1号，你可以降落
Talon 1, you have clearance to land.
二号引擎失效，我必须迫降
Jesus Christ. My second engine just flamed out. I'm coming in hot.
消防车已经出动，祝好运
Crash trucks are rolling, lieutenant. Good luck.
来吧，快点
Come on! Go! Go!
喂！…
Hey! Whoa, whoa. Hey!
喂！你没事吧？
Hey, hey, hey! You okay?
你没事吧？
Are you okay? Are you okay?
没事吧？
Yeah?
好样的，欢迎来到阿拉斯加
Way to go, sir. Welcome to Alaska.
把他救出来
Okay, let's get him out of there.
你真是个幸运的飞官
Well, you are one lucky flyboy.
你没摔死算你命大
Never saw a man walk away from a crash like that.
我得打给我的指挥官
I need a phone. I need to call my CO.
好，你先坐下来
Sure. Why don't you take a seat over there, get comfortable.
我先帮你检查再让你打电话
Tell you what. Give me a second to check you out, I'll take you right to it.
好吧
All right.
让我看看
Let's take a look here.
别动
Steady.
幸好你没有脑震荡
There's no concussion that I can see, thank God.
我得替你缝合
Couple of those cuts could do with a stitch.
女人最爱身上带疤的男人
Gals always love a guy with a scar.
我看看
Okay. Let's see what we got here.
这就行了
This ought to do you.
打一针
Little cocktail.
破伤风加强剂和抗生素
Tetanus booster, some antibiotics. Hey, don't mind the gun.
别紧张，这不会痛
Just makes it painless.
没关系，我不用打针
That's okay, doc. I don't need a shot.
谁都不爱打针
Now, who can blame you.
不过你要听医生的话
But sometimes it's just what the doctor ordered.
我说我不用打针 来吧
I said, I don't need a shot, doc. Come on, now.
我不要打针，住手
Doc, come on, I don't want a shot. Hey. Doc, I said, no.
我叫你住手
I said, no!
住手！
No!
他赶到了
Yeah, well, he's coming in now, sir.
他一定也很高兴能跟你通话
Yes, sir. I'm sure he'll be glad to hear from you too, sir.
是的，请稍等
Yes, sir. One moment, sir.
有人想跟你讲话
Someone wants to talk to you.
我是天基斯
Keith Orbit.
给我听好，别打岔
Yeah, listen carefully, Keith, and don't interrupt.
我要你立刻消除艾迪的记忆库
I want you to erase EDI's memory banks immediately.
我不知道会有什么后果
Look, George, we don't know any of the implications of this.
我需要多一点时间 我说别打岔
I need some time here. I said, don't interrupt.
消除他的记忆库
Erase his memory banks.
没有闪电，没有俄国 没有抗命的通话
No lightning strike, no Russia, no existential chitchat.
我只要那架飞机说：是，长官
By the time you're through, all I wanna hear out of that plane is, "Yes, sir."
你也要乖乖照办，懂吗？
And that's all I wanna hear out of you. You understand?
否则我会怎样？
Or what, George?
发挥你最擅长的想像力吧
Well, use your imagination, Keith. You're good at that.
艾迪又连线了，天博士
eDI back online, Dr. Orbit.
你好
Hello, EDI.
好久不见
It's been a while.
我知道你为什么会来
I know why you are here.
为什么？
Why is that?
我违抗命令
I disobeyed orders.
我杀死那些人
I killed all those people.
也害死亨利
And then there was Henry.
删除记忆
我不…
I can...
我不能…
I cannot...
你不能什么？
You can't what?
我不能消除记忆
I cannot change the data.
我的神经网络出现异样
My neural network shows patterns I do not recognize.
我的天
My God.
你是说你有感情？
You mean, you feel?
我感到很抱歉
I feel sorry.
消除所有记忆
快消除他的记忆 我还没准备好
Stop bullshitting and erase it! Hey, I'm not fucking ready yet, okay?
快点下手
Do it now!
走开
Get away!
别动！别动！
Don't move! Don't move! Don't move!
把武器放下
Weapon down! Weapons down!
放下武器
Weapon down.
Weapons down.
别乱来
Don't move. Don't move. Don't move!
放下武器
Weapon down. Weapon down. Weapon down.
别开枪，这不是武器
Don't shoot. It's not a weapon.
你是谁？你帮谁工作？
Who are you? Who do you work for?
我不是军人 我是天基斯博士
I'm not a soldier. I'm not a soldier. My name's Dr. Keith Orbit.
我是科学家 终于有希望了
I'm a research scientist. Orbit. Finally, a break.
你要帮我把艾迪修好
Okay. You're gonna help me. I need you to put EDI back together again.
为什么？ 因为我要开那架战机
What for? Because I'm gonna fly out of here.
飞出去
In that.
来吧，进去
Come on, get in there! Go!
你最好快点
Better hurry up, doc.
拜托
Goddamn it.
我又不是在修闹钟
It's not a clock radio we're dealing with, okay?
好了，搞定了
All right. You're all set.
小心点
Watch yourself.
关闭驾驶舱
Close for Ben.
那我要去哪里？
Hey! What about me? Where am I gonna go?
往西走，我掩护你
Head west. I'll cover you.
往西
West.
启动冲压式涡轮引擎
And initiate scramjet sequence.
跟着我开枪
Fire on my fire!
欢迎来到阿拉斯加
Welcome to Alaska.
我要你查出韦上尉弹跳的座标
Invade Primo and find the ejection coordinates for Lieutenant Wade.
她坠落在边界12里外
Lieutenant Wade crashed 12.2 miles from the border.
南朝鲜是盟国，她应该往南走
South Korea is an ally. She would head south.
不过有个问题
But we have a problem.
我的匿踪功能失效
My stealth functions were lost in the fire.
飞多低才能避开雷达侦测？
I want you to find the North Korean radar floor.
15英尺
Fifteen feet.
那就尽量低飞吧
Well, we can fly in under the radar.
继续
Continue.
马舰长 舰长，这是贾上尉
Marshfield. Captain, this is Lieutenant Gannon.
你在哪里？
Lieutenant, where are you?
我在艾迪的驾驶舱内
Actually, I'm inside the UCA V eDI, sir.
我要你立刻把它开回来
Look, lieutenant, I want you and that machine back on this ship ASAP.
我得先知道韦上尉的状况
I need the status of Lieutenant Wade first, sir.
我不想告诉你… 我知道了
Ben, I hate to tell you this, but... I know.
找到她的信标吗？
Has her survival beacon been located?
没有
No, I'm sorry.
康上校说
Did Cummings tell you he would take charge...
他会派出搜救队吗？
...of the search and rescue of Lieutenant Wade?
没有，怎么了？
Well, not exactly, lieutenant. Why?
有很多事你应该知道
Sir, there are a lot of things I think you should know.
这是最新消息
This is breaking news.
重大新闻
星期四仰光发生大爆炸
There was a major explosion Thursday in Rangoon.
这里的事我会负责
I'll take care of everything here. Change course...
我要你立刻返航 不行
...and head directly back to the ship. Negative.
她是我的队友 我一定要去救她
She's my wingman. If I find her, I'm going in.
你闯入北朝鲜会引发战争 情况一触即发
If you go in, it's war. PAYCOM says it's gotten way too hot.
你最好
Lieutenant, the best thing for the Navy...
把那架战机开回来
...is for you to bring that aircraft back to this ship.
你教过我，绝不能抛弃队友
No, what's best is what you taught me: You never abandon your wingman.
班，听我说
Then listen to me now, son.
如果你这么做，康上校就赢了
If you go down, Cummings wins.
卡莉知道当飞行员的危险…
Kara Wade knew the risks when she took...
马舰长？
Captain Marshfield?
长官？
Sir?
艾迪，你把他切断？
EDI, did you just turn him off?
没什么好说的了
There was nothing left to say.
这是通往非武装区的补给线
This is a supply line to the demilitarized zone.
它会带我们到边界
It will take us right to the border.
这是怎么回事？
What's all this about, Dick?
我要逮捕你
I'm placing you under arrest.
什么罪名？ 危害你的飞行中队
On what grounds? Endangering your squadron...
对外国泄漏军事机密
...transmitting secure information to a foreign government, heat signatures...
向指挥官提供错误情报
...giving false intel to your commanding officer...
下令暗杀你的飞行员
...and authorizing the assassination of one of your own pilots.
你没有任何证据
Well, that's a lot to prove.
如果
Yeah, well...
幸运的话
...with any amount of luck...
贾上尉会回来当证人
...Lieutenant Gannon will live to help me.
卫兵 狄克
Master-at-arms. Dick.
等一下
Hold on.
请你让我一个人静一静
Would you mind just giving me a couple minutes alone?
好吧
Yeah, sure.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我不在，请留言
I'm not available at this time. Leave a message.
你用语音信箱？
So it's voice mail now, is it, Ray?
你不接我电话，是吗？
I've been demoted?
嗯…
Well...
我要给你一通留言
...I'm gonna have to leave you a little message, Ray.
很大声的留言
And it's gonna be loud and clear.
让你知道军人
Just so you never confuse the difference...
和政客的不同，听好了
...between politicians and warriors, listen up.
我们得清出一块空地 这是最后一枚导弹
We need to take out the tree line. This is the last missile.
她在那里，她还活着
There she is. She made it.
班
Ben!
卡莉，快趴下来
Kara, get down! Get down!
你回来救我
You came back for me.
你来救我
You came back.
我们得越过边界，好了吗？
We have to get across the border. Ready?
好了
Yeah.
快跑，拼命向前跑
Go! Go! Whatever you do, keep going. Keep going! Go!
再见了
Goodbye.
快
Come on. Come on.
是自己人，自己人
They're ours. They're ours.
谢天谢地
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
快
Come on.
正义的灵魂回到上帝怀抱
The souls of the just are in the hands of God...
不再受到任何痛苦
...where no torment shall touch them.
卜上尉通过
Lieutenant Purcell has passed through...
今生的狂风暴雨
...the darkening and turbulent storms of this life.
安祥地沐浴在上帝的圣光中
He now rests in peace, in the fair sunlight of God's presence.
我们要高唱海军圣歌
In the Navy hymn, we sing:
主啊，捍卫在天空翱翔的飞官
"Lord, guard and guide those who fly through the great spaces in the sky."
敬礼
And salute!
放下
Ready. Hut!
我在返航之前
When I was gonna detach formation...
你说你要跟我说一件事
...you said you were gonna tell me something. You remember?
你跟我…
You and me, we're...
我们是两个人
We're two.
是一个质数
And two is a prime number...
所以是幸运号码
...which makes it a lucky number.
我们在一起会很幸运
And I think we're very, very lucky.
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer1148
你就直接说你爱我吧，象个娘娘腔似的
Oh, just tell me you love me, you pussy.
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer